pioneerelectronics.com 2013-11-16

# Privacy Policy | Pioneer Electronics USA

**Privacy Policy**

Pioneer Electronics (USA) Inc. (“Pioneer”) has created this Privacy Policy to explain the privacy practices for the pioneerelectronics.com and pioneerdjusa.com websites, including their microsites (each, a “Website,” and collectively, “Websites”).  Pioneer reserves the right to change its privacy policies at any time by posting the revised Privacy Policy.  Each time you visit or use a Website, the current version of the Privacy Policy applies.  Please look for notices on the home page for periodic updates.  If you do not agree to the Privacy Policy, do not use any Websites.

**What information does Pioneer collect?**

The information we learn from you helps us personalize and improve your shopping and viewing experience on the Websites.  The following are the types of information we gather.

**Information you give us:**  We receive and store information you choose to enter on our Websites and use it to provide you with the information, products and services you are interested in receiving.  If you wish to sign up for email newsletters or purchase and/or register Pioneer products, you will need to set up an account.  When you set up an account, you will provide your name, mailing address, e-mail address, and telephone number (optional), and create a password. Actual purchases will also require payment and delivery information.  During the registration or account setup process or at other places on the Websites, you may have the opportunity to indicate areas about which you would like to receive more information.  Finally, when you register a Pioneer product, we may additionally request demographic information to help understand our customers better, but it is always up to you whether to provide it and is not necessary for registration.

We use information you provide to offer a variety of benefits, such as notification of special offers we think you'll find valuable.  You may also be asked whether you would like to participate in future surveys.  Participation in any of these programs is, of course, at your option, and you may unsubscribe later if you change your mind. 

**Automatic Information:** We automatically receive and record certain types of information whenever you interact with us. This information may include the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your domain name, country location, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and log files (entry and exit points/pages, date/time of access). We use this information to learn how visitors use the site, to remember your visits, and to diagnose problems.  

**Cookies and pixel tags:**   Like many other websites, the Websites use “cookies” (small text files) to record your activity while visiting and enable us to personalize your Web browsing experience, including allowing our system to record your logon and password.  Additionally, “pixel tags” (lines of code and an image) are placed selectively on the Websites and in advertisements that link to it to analyze general usage patterns of visitors. These pixel tags are programmed to collect only non-personally identifiable information. We also use pixel tags in email announcements to measure, as a whole, the level of interest in them.

If you do not want Pioneer or its vendors to deploy browser cookies when you visit the Websites, you may set your browser to reject cookies.  Doing so may disable the Websites’ ability to retain information you have provided and affect the use some of the products, features, functions, or services on the Websites.

Anonymous session information is collected and analyzed by Google Inc. using Google Analytics.  For more information about Google, Google's use of cookies, and Google’s privacy practices, please click here: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.

**What other communications are there?**

**Email:**  We would like to set up a dialogue with our customers through the use of email.  We hope to provide you with useful and interesting information on new technologies and also provide you a channel for feedback.  If at any time you wish to remove your email address from Pioneer's email list, you can do so by selecting the opt-out option in a Pioneer email or by updating “My Account” online.

**Links & Forums:** We provide you with external links to sites not affiliated with Pioneer that we believe can offer you useful information and services.  Any non-Pioneer website, application or other content you may access from a Website or a Pioneer product will have its own privacy policies and practices, which you will need to review.  Pioneer is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these providers and you access and use them at your own risk.  

Public forums such as chat rooms, message boards, and news groups may also be made available to visitors to our Websites.  Information disclosed in public forums is public information, and caution should be exercised when disclosing any personal or other identifying information.  You may not be able to change or remove public postings once posted, and such personally identifiable information may be used by visitors to those pages to send unsolicited messages.  Pioneer is not responsible for any consequences that may occur from the use of information that you choose to submit to public forums and sites.

**Advertising:   ** Pioneer uses one or more companies to place advertisements for our products on third party sites.  Cookies and other technologies such as web beacons or tags are used to measure the effectiveness of those ads and to determine the display of content and advertising to you based on your interests, both on the Websites and on third-party sites you may visit.  To support this interest-based advertising, we and companies with whom we have contracted may use information about your visits to our site and other websites. The information collected and used by this process is anonymous and does not enable a third party to identify you individually.

Although we hope that you find the display of advertising to you based on your interests valuable, if you prefer not to participate, you can always opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website here: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

**How is information protected?**

The Websites use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software to protect your personal data.  SSL encrypts personal information as it is transmitted over the Internet.  Pioneer uses firewalls between its internal network and the Web, and network servers are protected by both physical and system level security in a data center facility made accessible on a need-to-know basis using unique IDs.  The Websites are registered with a site identification authority that enables your browser to confirm our identity before you send any information.  During product registration and at purchase checkout stage, Pioneer uses a server ID (or a digital certificate) together with industry-standard 128-bit SSL encryption to protect sensitive customer information during both transmission and storage.

While we follow reasonable procedures and updates according to industry standards in an effort to protect your information, no security system is perfect and we cannot guarantee that your information will remain secure in all circumstances.

**Does Pioneer share my personal information?**

Pioneer does not sell or rent personal information to third-party marketers, data collection companies or any other entities.  Pioneer shares personal information with selected fulfillment companies solely to fulfill your requests such as purchases and to provide consent-based marketing support, and may allow access as needed for technical support of our systems.  Each company is required to keep the information confidential and secure and to use it only for the limited purpose for which we share it.  Pioneer may also disclose personal information if required by law, such as in response to a subpoena or similar legal process, or to report activities we reasonably believe to be unlawful, or as necessary to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims brought against us.  In the event that Pioneer, or substantially all of its assets, is acquired, customer information may be one of the transferred assets.  Aggregated (consolidated) demographic information that does not reveal individual information may be shared with third party advertisers to describe our customer base.  This information is purely statistical in nature and cannot be tied to the individuals who provided the data.

When you click the “Like” button for a Pioneer product, you are providing that information to Facebook, Inc., and its use will be governed by Facebook’s Data Use Policy:  https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/

**Children**

Pioneer does not provide products or services to children or knowingly collect or solicit information from children under the age of 13.  If we become aware that a user is under the age of 13 and has provided personally identifiable information without the prior consent of a parent or guardian, we will remove the user's personally identifiable information from our files.

**What if I have questions?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or information collected about you, please write to us:  Pioneer Electronics (USA) Inc., Internet Team, 1925 East Dominguez Street, Long Beach, CA 90810. 

May 21, 2013
